Inventory of the David Monroe Shoup papers, 1904-1983
Hoover Institution Archives
David Monroe Shoup papers
1904-1983
76027
Hoover Institution Archives
31 manuscript boxes, 4 oversize boxes, 22 sound recordings, 9 motion picture film reels (18.0 linear feet)
Correspondence, memoranda, writings, printed matter, photographs, sound recordings, and motion picture film relating to the Tarawa campaign, other World War II campaigns in the Pacific Theater, post-war activities of the Marine Corps, service as the Commandant of the Marine Corps, and the Vietnam War.
Shoup, David Monroe, 1904-
Access
Collection is open for research.
Use copies of some sound recordings, video recordings, or motion picture material in this collection are available for immediate access. To access other sound recordings, video recordings, or motion picture material during your visit, please contact the Archives at least two working days before your arrival. We will then advise you of the accessibility of the material you wish to see or hear. Please note that not all audiovisual material is immediately accessible.
Acquisition Information
Acquired by the Hoover Institution Archives in 1976.
Accruals
Materials may have been added to the collection since this finding aid was prepared. To determine if this has occurred, find the collection in Stanford University's online catalog at http://searchworks.stanford.edu/. Materials have been added to the collection if the number of boxes listed in the online catalog is larger than the number of boxes listed in this finding aid.
Biographical Note
1904 Born, Battle Ground, Indiana
1926 Graduate of DePauw University, Greencastle, Indiana
1926 July 20 Commissioned a second lieutenant in the U.S. Marine Corps
1926-1941 Various postings within the Marine Corps, including an atypical post with the Civilian Conservation Corps in 1933-1934; promoted through ranks to Major
1942 Arrived in New Zealand; served as G-3, Operations and Training Officer of the 2nd Marine Division
1943 Promoted to Colonel; placed in command of the 2nd Marines, the spearhead of the assault on Tarawa; earned the Medal of Honor and a Purple Heart
1944 Served as Chief of Staff, 2nd Marine Division
1944-1947 Returned to the U.S.; served as Logistics Officer, Division of Plans and Policies, Headquarters Marine Corps
1947 Served as Commanding Officer, Service Command, Fleet Marine Force (FMF), Pacific
1949 Served as Division Chief of Staff, 1st Marine Division, Camp Pendleton, California
1950-1952 Commanding Officer of the Basic School, Quantico, Virginia
1953-1955 Served as Fiscal Director of the Marine Corps
1956-1957 Promoted to Major General; served as Inspector General for Recruit Training
1957-1958 Served as Commanding General of the 1st Marine Division, Camp Pendleton, California, and 3rd Marine Division, Okinawa
1959 Commanding General of the Marine Corps Recruit Depot, Parris Island, South Carolina
1959 August 12 Nominated by President Dwight D. Eisenhower to be the 22nd Commandant of the Marine Corps
1960-1963 Served as 22nd Commandant of the Marine Corps; promoted to four-star general rank; served on the Joint Chiefs of Staff
1963 Retired to Arlington, Virginia; became an outspoken critic of the war in Vietnam
1983 Died; buried in Arlington National Cemetery
Scope and Content of Collection
The papers document the military career of World War II veteran General David S. Shoup, along with his post-military speaking and writing, in personal files, correspondence, speeches, writings, sound recordings, and film footage.
Materials include documentation of the many military positions Shoup held as he steadily rose through the ranks of the Marine Corps, taking on responsibilities in training, fiscal reorganization, and logistics, a process well described in his personal files, correspondence, speeches, and photographs.
The collection also contains documentation relating to Shoup's World War II tours, particularly the assault against well-entrenched Japanese defenders at Tarawa, where Shoup, as the senior officer ashore, directed the costly suppression of Japanese resistance. Marines, landing on boats that often became lodged on coral reefs, had to wade in for hundreds of yards in the face of withering fire. His heroism on Tarawa earned Shoup the Medal of Honor and a Purple Heart. Materials about the campaign include a military diary, photographs, research materials, and articles.
There is significant documentation of Shoup's tenure as the 22nd Commandant of the Marine Corps from 1960 to 1963 in speeches, correspondence, and photographs. Shoup's leadership brought changes to the Marine Corps: he eliminated the use of swagger sticks, minimized base ceremonies during commandant visits, and upgraded the combat readiness of all Marine units. Vietnam became a pressing policy issue during this time, and Shoup opposed any commitment of U.S. combat forces in Southeast Asia.
After retirement, Shoup's skepticism about involvement in Vietnam deepened and became public as he wrote and spoke out about his concerns. His writings and collected printed materials display his desire to speak out against escalating the Vietnam War in the print media, as well as testifying before Congress.
Tarawa, Battle of, 1943.; United States--Armed Forces.; United States. Marine Corps--Officers.; United States. Marine Corps. Division, 2d.; Moving-pictures.; Phonorecords.; Vietnam War, 1961-1975.; World War, 1939-1945--Campaigns--Pacific Ocean.; World War, 1939-1945.
- Personal Files, 1904-1970 (Boxes 1-5, 31)
  Scope and Contents note
  Includes general biographical information, a patent, citations, awards, and a set of personal files of correspondence, notes, orders, and other printed materials.
  - Biographical file, 1934, 1943 (Box 1)
  - Journal/notebook, circa 1927, undated (Box 1)
  - Citations, certificates, and awards, 1926-1944 (Box 1)
  - Honors and awards, 1943-1970 (Box 1)
  - Awards, oversize, 1928-1961 (Box 31)
  - Patent no. 2,100,982, a device for blacking sights of weapons, 1937 (Box 1)
  - Receipts, correspondence, and photographs, 1951-1956 (Box 1)
  - Invitations and menus, 1933-1960 (Box 1)
  - Files, 1904-1968
    Personal correspondence, notes, orders, brochures, and other collected printed materials, organized in numbered files, then chronologically.
    - 1, 1904-1961; 1926-1945 (bulk) (Box 2)
    - 2, 1944-1968; 1945-1963 (bulk) (Box 2)
    - 3, 1958-1961 (Box 3)
    - 4, 1959-1964 (Box 3)
    - 1944-1952 (Box 3)
    - 1956-1957 June (Box 4)
    - 1957 July-1963 (Box 5)
- Correspondence, 1936-1969 (Boxes 5-10)
  Arranged in chronological order. See also: Commandant of the Marine Corps Files for additional correspondence.
  - 1936, 1943 (Box 5)
  - 1949-1955 (Box 6)
  - 1957-1959 (Box 7)
    Includes declassified records returned to file after January 2016 release by Hoover (in 1 April 1958 - 30 June 1958).
  - Congratulatory correspondence, 1959-1969
    Generally about promotion to Commandant of the Marine Corps, as well as for his 1969 Atlantic article.
    - Files 1-5, 1959-1962 (Box 8)
    - Files 6-7, 1959-1962, 1969 (Box 9)
      Including congratulations on "The New American Militarism" article in The Atlantic, 1969.
    - 1967-1969 (Box 10)
    - 1969 (Box 10)
- Speeches, 1943-1972 (Boxes 10-11)
  Speeches given while not holding the position of Commandant of the Marine Corps. See also: Commandant of the Marine Corps Files for additional speeches.
  - General speeches (Box 10)
  - 1951 (Box 10)
  - Depauw University 25th anniversary, building dedication, speech and photograph, 1951 (Box 10)
  - Notes, 1955 (Box 10)
  - 1960 January 4 (Box 10)
  - circa 1965 (Box 10)
  - 1967-1968 (Box 10)
  - Vietnam testimony, 1967-1968 (Box 10)
    - 1968 (Box 10)
    - 1969 (Box 10)
    - 1969-1971 (Box 10)
  - Senate Foreign Relations Committee, 1971 May 25 (Box 10)
  - circa 1972 (Box 10)
  - Quotations, undated (Box 10)
  - Undated (Box 10)
  - Unclassified speeches, 1943-1957 (Box 11)
    Includes a speech titles index for each numbered series.
  - Unclassified speeches, circa 1956 (Box 11)
- Military Positions Materials, 1904-1959 (Boxes 12, 31)
  Materials relating to a variety of positions Shoup held in the Marine Corps.
  - Military Commissions, 1927-1959 (Box 31)
  - Call sign notebook, undated (Box 12)
  - Quotes, undated (Box 12)
  - Correspondence, including clippings, 1943-1944 (Box 12)
  - Second Marine Division, 1943-1944 (Box 12)
    Three folders.
  - Basic School documents, 1953-1956 (Box 12)
  - Marine Corps Fiscal Division notes and budget manual, 1953 (Box 12)
  - Marine Corps fiscal estimates, 1904-1907 (Box 12)
  - Marine Corps Fiscal Division, 1953 (Box 12)
  - Marine training report, 1956 (Box 12)
  - Formations and supplies notes, oversize, undated (Box 31)
- Commandant of the Marine Corps Files, 1959-1965 (Boxes 13-20, 29)
  Materials created while Shoup was the Commandant of the Marine Corps (CMC). See also: Correspondence and Speeches for additional information.
  - Speeches, 1960-1965
    A majority of the speeches included were given during Shoup's time as Commandant of the Marine Corps. Includes a speech titles index for each numbered series.
    - Numbered 1-30, 1960 January-August (Box 13)
    - Numbered 1-25, 1960 October - 1961 December (Box 13)
    - Numbered 26-33, 1960 October - 1961 December (Box 14)
    - Numbered 1-48, 1961 December - 1963 December (Box 14)
    - Unnumbered, circa 1961-1965 (Box 14)
  - Alphabetical correspondence, 1959-1963
    - A-H (Box 15)
    - H-M (Box 16)
    - M-S (Box 17)
    - S-Z (Box 18)
  - General officers correspondence, 1959-1962 (Box 19)
    Two folders.
  - President of the United States correspondence, 1961-1963 (Box 19)
  - Presidential inauguration materials, 1961 (Box 19)
  - Press conferences, favorable, 1961-1962 (Box 19)
  - Press conferences, unfavorable, 1961-1962 (Box 19)
  - Press coverage, 1962 (Box 19)
  - Remarks, 1961-1963 (Box 19)
  - Utterances, notes, and miscellany, including notes on becoming the Commandant of the Marine Corps, 1959-1963 (Box 19)
  - "Muzzling of the Military," Stennis hearings in Senate, 1961-1962 (Box 19)
  - "Muzzling of the Military," correspondence and clippings, circa 1961-1962 (Box 20)
    Six folders.
  - Charleston News and Courier editorial, 1962 (Box 20)
  - Karou Omine visit, 1963 (Box 20)
  - Chart folio, flight schedule to Japan, U.S. Naval Oceanographic Office, 1963 September-October (Box 29)
  - Far East tour documents and photographs, 1963 (Box 20)
  - Visit to the Royal Thai Marine Corps, circa 1963 (Box 20)
  - City of Los Angeles, oversize certificate in honor of General Shoup Day, 1963 August 20 (Box 29)
- Writings, 1965-1971 (Box 21)
  Contains articles written by Shoup after his retirement from the military.
  - Vietnam, 1965-1971 (Box 21)
  - "Military Leadership and McNamara,", circa 1968 (Box 21)
  - "Let's Dare Think About Lasting World Peace,", 1969 (Box 21)
  - "The New American Militarism," The Atlantic, 1969 (Box 21)
  - "New American Militarism," reprinted, Businessmen's Educational Fund, New York, 1970 (Box 21)
  - "The China Expedition,", undated (Box 21)
- Tarawa Materials, 1943-1968 (Boxes 21-22, 31)
  Various materials documenting the 1943 Tarawa campaigns, including items original to the time as well as those collected or written later, arranged in chronological order. See also: Photographs.
  - Small notebook/military diary, 1943 (Box 21)
  - Tarawa operations report, 1943 (Box 21)
    Includes signed photographs.
  - Tarawa materials, 1943 (Box 21)
  - Tarawa Atoll charts, 1943 (Box 21)
  - Photograph book captured at Tarawa, 1943 (Box 21)
  - Tarawa Quartermaster's joke, 1943 (Box 21)
  - Camp Tarawa aerial photograph, oversize, circa 1943 (Box 31)
  - Tarawa landing photograph, oversize, mounted, 1943 (Box 31)
  - Christening of the USS Tarawa by Zola Shoup, 1944-1946 (Box 21)
  - "The Tarawa Campaign," an address by Col. Robert R. McCormick, 1946 (Box 21)
  - "The Battle for Tarawa," Capt. James R. Stockman, USMC Historical Section, 1947 (Box 21)
  - "Some of My Thoughts on Tarawa," David Shoup, circa 1954 (Box 22)
  - Tarawa articles, circa 1954-1957 (Box 22)
  - "The Bloody Epic that Was Tarawa," New York Times Magazine, 1958 November 16 (Box 22)
  - Amphibious Warfare Sea Power Symposium, Tarawa photographic reprints, 1960 (Box 22)
  - Tarawa articles, 1962 (Box 22)
  - "Tarawa, My Last Battle," Kiyoshi Ota with Keith S. Williams, 1964 (Box 22)
  - Tarawa materials, 1968 (Box 22)
  - Tarawa 25th anniversary materials, 1968 (Box 22)
    Includes reprinted photographs.
  - Uncommon Valor pamphlet, including Tarawa photograph, undated (Box 31)
- Photographs, 1942-1971 (Boxes 23-31)
  Contains official photographs, snapshots, and personal photographs, arranged chronologically.
  - Hawaii, circa 1942 (Box 23)
  - 1942 July (Box 23)
  - Battle of Tarawa, 1943 (Box 23)
    See also: Tarawa research materials for additional information.
  - Battle of Tarawa and after, 1943 (Box 23)
  - Tarawa, 1943 (Box 23)
    Includes related correspondence.
  - 1943 (Box 23)
  - Shoup, 1943-1944 (Box 23)
  - War scenes, possibly Tarawa, circa 1943-1944 (Box 23)
  - War scenes, 1944 August (Box 23)
  - War scenes, circa 1944 (Box 23)
  - Official photographs, circa 1944 (Box 23)
  - Official photographs of officers, 1945 (Box 23)
  - War publicity photos, 1945 (Box 23)
  - Ceremonies: Medal of Honor, Promotion, and CMC, 1945-1959 (Box 23)
  - Commissioning of the USS Tarawa, 1945-1946 (Box 23)
  - Bikini Atoll atomic test, 1946 (Box 23)
  - 1947 January (Box 23)
  - 1948 (Box 23)
  - Basic School, Quantico, Virginia, circa 1951 (Box 24)
  - 9th JCOC, Marine Corps Schools, 1951 (Box 24)
  - Portraits and negatives, 1955 (Box 24)
  - 2nd Division Sword Monument speech, 1955 (Box 31)
  - Parris Island, South Carolina, 1956 December (Box 24)
  - 1957 January, July, and August (Box 24)
  - 1957 September (Box 24)
  - 1957 October (Box 24)
  - 1957 November (Box 24)
  - First Division miscellany, 1957 (Box 24)
  - Congressional Medal of Honor Society, 1957 (Box 24)
  - 1957-1959 (Box 24)
  - Camp Hansen Typhoon, Okinawa, 1958 January (Box 24)
  - 1958 March (Box 25)
  - 1958 April (Box 25)
  - 1958 May, June, and July (Box 25)
  - 1958 October (Box 25)
  - 1958 November (Box 25)
  - 1958 December (Box 25)
  - Taipei, General Shu and General Shoup, 1958 (Box 25)
  - DePauw University, 1958 (Box 25)
  - First Marine Division History, 1958 (Box 25)
  - First Marine Aircraft Wing, 1958 (Box 25)
  - Quarters, Okinawa, 1958-1959 (Box 25)
  - Cloth of Okinawa, circa 1958-1959 (Box 25)
  - 1959 (Box 25)
  - 1959 March (Box 25)
  - All-Marine Boxing Champion, 1959 (Box 26)
  - Shoup, life story for Commandant ceremony, 1959 (Box 26)
  - Parris Island, South Carolina, 1959 (Box 26)
  - Covington, Indiana Veteran's Day celebration honoring General Shoup, 1960 (Box 26)
  - Naval Academy visit, 1960 (Box 26)
  - General Franke, Secretary of the Navy, signed, 1960 (Box 31)
  - Taiwan Marine inspection slides, 1961 (Box 26)
  - Salute to Admiral Arleigh Burke, 1961 (Box 26)
  - Commandant of the Marine Corps (CMC), 1961 (Box 26)
  - Visits, 1961-1963 (Box 26)
  - Visits, oversize, 1961-1963 (Box 31)
  - Cabinet/Staff, oversize, 1961-1963 (Box 31)
  - Signed Cabinet/Staff, oversize, 1961-1963 (Box 31)
  - Naval Academy visit, 1962 (Box 26)
  - Fort Still, Indiana visit, 1962 (Box 26)
  - Commandant of the Marine Corps visit to JUSMAG Bankok, 1962 (Box 26)
  - 1963 (Box 27)
  - President Kennedy and Shoup, 1963 (Box 27)
  - Distinguished Service Medal, with President Johnson, 1964 (Box 27)
  - Johnson White House, 1964 (Box 31)
  - Birthday, 1964 (Box 27)
  - Parade photo signed by Herbert Humphrey, 1965 (Box 27)
  - 1967 (Box 27)
  - 1970-1971 (Box 27)
  - Portrait, undated (Box 27)
  - Personal photos, undated (Box 27)
  - Honorary degree, undated (Box 27)
  - Color photographs, undated (Box 27)
  - Third Marine Division, undated (Box 27)
  - Military visits, circa 1945-1950 (Box 27)
  - Military training, undated (Box 27)
  - Miscellany, undated (Box 27)
  - Photographic books and albums
    - Inauguration of John F. Kennedy, 1961 (Box 27)
    - Chinese visit, circa 1961 (Box 28)
    - Korean visit, 1961 (Box 29)
    - Camp Murphy, Philippines visit, 1961 (Box 30)
    - U.S. First Fleet Exercise, United States Navy and Marine Corps, 1961 November 18 (Box 28)
    - Visit of the President of the United States and Distinguished guests to the U.S. Atlantic Fleet, 1962 April 13-14 (Box 28)
    - Marine Corps Base Combat Swimming Team, Twentynine Palms, California, 1963 (Box 27)
    - Special issue for the 9th Marine Anniversary Brigade, 1963 October (Box 27)
    - 20th Anniversary of the 2nd Marine Division, D.M. Shoup, a lifetime of photographs, 1963 (Box 30)
- Collected Printed Materials, 1907-1983 (Boxes 31-35)
  Consists of collected clippings, printed materials, and research books. Shoup often wrote or was quoted in the materials.
  - Clippings, 1944-1968 (Box 32)
  - Clippings, 1967-1983 (Box 33)
  - Clippings, oversize, 1960-1968 (Box 31)
  - Fountain-Warren Democrat, Attica, Fountain County, Indiana, 1907 June 13 (Box 34)
  - The Bulletin, San Francisco, 1928 August 18 (Box 34)
  - Congressional Record, Senate, vol. 106, no. 4, 1960 January 12 (Box 34)
  - Congressional Record, Senate, vol. 106, no. 44, 1960 March 9 (Box 34)
  - Congressional Record, House, vol. 109, no. 47, 1963 April 1 (Box 34)
  - Congressional Record, House, vol. 113, no. 25, 1967 February 20 (Box 34)
  - Congressional Record, Senate, vol. 115, no. 52, 1969 March 26 (Box 34)
  - "A Way of Thinking," typescript by Dr. Albert Burke, circa 1970 (Box 34)
  - Newsweek, 1971 November 29 (Box 34)
  - "Our President, Herbert Hoover," William J. Marsh (age 11 years), signed by the author, 1930 (Box 35)
  - Follow Me! The Story of the Second Marine Division in World War II, by Richard W. Johnston, Random House, 1948 (Box 35)
  - Khrushchev in America: Full Texts of the Speeches Given by Khrushchev on His Tour of the United States in September 1959, 1960 (Box 35)
  - The Chien Nhan Dan, People's Strategy, 1960 (Box 35)
  - Nation's Business: A Useful Look Ahead Magazine, 1962 October (Box 35)
  - Intercom: Your Guide to the World Affairs Field, 1966 July-August (Box 35)
  - Kaikishu, Japanese maritime self-defense force, Admiral Togo, undated (Box 35)
  - Sons of Indiana: Stories of Indiana's Famous Sons, Indiana Bell, undated (Box 35)
  - How to Save our Republic, by Dr. George W. Crane, undated (Box 35)
  - Japanese Lesson Book, undated (Box 35)
- Memorabilia, 1941, 1954-1962, undated (Box 1, 30-31)
  - Inauguration license plates, 1954-1962 (Box 30)
  - Remington Arms Company posters, undated (Box 31)
  - World War II signal cylinder: Signal, Ground, Amber Star Cluster M22, 1941 (Box 1)
- Filmstrips, undated (Box 1)
  - Project Crossroads, Able and Baker nuclear tests, 35 mm film
- Audiovisual Materials, 1959-1972, undated (Tape cabinet, Record cabinet, Film shelf)
  - Sound recordings, 1959-1972
    Arranged by format, then chronologically.
    - Admiral Burke's party, seven inch sound reel, possibly 1961 (Tape cabinet)
    - W.R. Epsy, "talking letter,", 1963 (Tape cabinet)
      Includes his experiences in World War I, Marine Aviation in the Azores, and Marines. Given to Shoup as the Commandant of the Marine Corps. Three inch sound reel; also includes a slide.
    - Navy-Marine Corps Memorial, "in appreciation of your support in furthering the establishment of a Navy-Marine Corps Memorial Stadium, Annapolis, Maryland,", before 1959 (Record cabinet)
    - Khrushchev in America, Eisenhower-Khrushchev meetings, CBS Radio Network, 1959 (Record cabinet)
    - The Kings of Pentagonia, Annual Wallow Skit, Military Order of the Carabao, 1960 February 6 (Record cabinet)
    - Sounds of Marine Corps Boot Camp, San Diego, Parris Island, Gold Star Recordings, 1960 (Record cabinet)
    - Tatoo Delft, Marine Band of the Royal Netherlands Navy Marinierskapel der Koninklijke Marine, 1960 (Record cabinet)
    - Parade of the Champions, Band of the Royal Netherlands Navy, circa 1960 (Record cabinet)
    - Marines on Parade, Marine Band of the Royal Netherlands Navy, circa 1960 (Record cabinet)
    - Tradition: Favorite Songs of the United States Marines, U.S. Marine Band and Marine Corps Officer's Basic School Chorus, circa 1960 (Record cabinet)
    - "The President's Own," United States Marine Band, Lieutenant Colonel Albert Schoepper, Director, circa 1960 (Record cabinet)
    - Alliance for Progress, programs and lectures on Latin America and promoting Western Hemisphere understanding, Westinghouse Company, 1962 (Record cabinet)
    - Dedication dinner for the Donald W. Douglas Engineering Product Development Center, Douglans Aircraft Company, Inc., 1962 (Record cabinet)
    - "A Moment with General David Shoup," part 1, concerning Shoup's career; military issues, such as the nuclear test ban treaty; and his personal hobbies, 1963 November 9 (Record cabinet)
      Access note
      Use copy reference number: 76027_a_0001702
    - United States Marine Band, Lt. Col. A.F. Schoepper, Director, conducting, including the General Shoup March, circa 1960-1963 (Record cabinet)
      Use copy reference number: 76027_a_0001703
      1. General Shoup March; 2. Marine's Hymn - Wm. Jones, soloist; 3. Semper Fidelis; 4. King Cotton.
    - The Fort Henry Retreat Ceremonial, recorded live at Fort Henry, Kingston, Ontario, Canada exactly as performed there since 1812, 1963 (Record cabinet)
    - The National Cultural Center presents: The United States Marine Band, 1963 (Record cabinet)
    - The United States Marine Corps Band, circa 1960-1963 (Record cabinet)
    - The Commandant's Own, U.S. Marine Drum and Bugle Corps, 1970 (Record cabinet)
    - America's First Man in Orbit, John H. Glenn in Friendship 7, Nelson Doubleday, Inc., 1972 (Record cabinet)
    - Semper Fi lacquer disc, undated (Record cabinet)
      Use copy reference number: 76027_a_0001701
      The three cuts on side A are a male chorus singing "Semper Fi," a male/female duet whose title seems to be "That's A Lot of El Toro," and the Star Spangled Banner. Side B is two cuts of a male chorus, the second also being "Semper Fi."
    - Japanese record, undated (Record cabinet)
  - Motion picture film reels, 1960-1964, undated
    - King and Queen of Afghanistan, 16mm film, 500 feet, undated (Film shelf shelf)
    - General Shoup interviewed by Von Fremd, CBS Washington, 16mm film, circa 1961-1963 (Film shelf shelf)
    - Salute to the Navy, 16mm film, 1000 feet, undated (Film shelf shelf)
    - A Force in Readiness, 2 copies, 16mm film, 950 feet, circa 1961-1963 (Film shelf shelf)
    - "Tarawa," The Twentieth Century, CBS Television Film Service Operations, 2 copies, 16mm film, 1892 feet, undated (Film shelf shelf)
    - The Story of a Marine, 16mm film, 900 feet, circa 1960-1963 (Film shelf shelf)
    - Presented to General David S. Shoup, Commandant of the Marine Corps, 1960-1964, from the Old and New Breed, with Second Division and Marine Corps Symbols, 16mm film, after 1964 (Film shelf shelf)